A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program, Director, Office Files of Bernard McDonald FA606
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program Related Investments, 1979-1987; III
  These files contain correspondence, memoranda, and some program reviews, all regarding Program Related Investments (PRIs). PRI recipients include the Mississippi Action for Community Education (1979-1987) and the Southern Development Foundation's (SDF) Federation of Southern Cooperatives (1979-1987). The files on the SDF include background on an FBI investigation and a Government Accountability Office (GAO) audit of the organization.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Community Development Corporations (CDCs) -- General -- List of Ford Foundation CDC Grants, National Congress for Community Economic Development (NCCED) Meeting, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Community Development Corporations (CDCs) -- Memoranda Re: Impact of Federal Budget Cuts, 1981 February 11-June 19 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Community Development Corporations (CDCs) -- Correspondence with Grantees, CDC/PRI Workshop, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Delta Enterprises -- Memoranda, Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - General -- Project Review Memoranda and Agenda, Reports on PRI Grants, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - General -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Status Report, PRIs, Forward Planning, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - General -- Planning Memoranda, Correspondence Re: Proposals, Meeting Reports (1 of 4), 1982 November-1983 February (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General -- Planning Memoranda, Correspondence Re: Proposals, Meeting Reports (2 of 4), 1983 March (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General -- Planning Memoranda, Correspondence Re: Proposals, Meeting Reports (3 of 4), 1983 April-July (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General -- Planning Memoranda, Correspondence Re: Proposals, Meeting Reports, Background (4 of 4), 1983 August-1984 January (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - General -- Memoranda Re: Internal Policy, Program Review Papers, DAP Grant Action, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - General -- Planning Memoranda, Status Updates, Funding Request, 1986 January 8-1987 July 15 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Mississippi Action for Community Education (MACE) -- Memoranda, Correspondence, 1979-1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - National Black Archives of Film and Broadcasting -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Proposal, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Southern Development Foundation -- Federation of Southern Cooperatives -- Site Visit Memoranda and Background on FBI Investigation and General Accounting Office (GAO) Audit of Grantee (1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Southern Development Foundation -- Federation of Southern Cooperatives -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: PRI (2 of 2), 1980-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)